<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SpaSES Lab @ Boise State on SpaSES Lab</title>
    <link>https://spaseslab.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SpaSES Lab @ Boise State on SpaSES Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://spaseslab.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Netlify</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/collection/day02/01-netlify/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/collection/day02/01-netlify/</guid>
      <description>So far, we&amp;rsquo;ve been leveraging GitHub Pages for publishing. This works great, but for blogdown we&amp;rsquo;ll start using Netlify. Let&amp;rsquo;s start RIGHT NOW with a site we&amp;rsquo;ve already built and published.
Pre-requisites     Pick either your postcards site, or your distill site from day 01. Refresh your memory- which repository was it again?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A GitHub profile</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/collection/day01/01-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/collection/day01/01-github/</guid>
      <description>Profile      https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/personalizing-your-profile
Pin projects to profile      https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/pinning-items-to-your-profile
Profile README     This is new! Let&amp;rsquo;s do it:
 https://docs.github.com/en/github/setting-up-and-managing-your-github-profile/managing-your-profile-readme</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prework</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/collection/prework/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/collection/prework/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the Introducing Yourself Online workshop! We look forward to meeting you. Before attending the workshop, please complete the following prework.
Set up RStudio Cloud     Sign up for a free RStudio Cloud account at https://rstudio.cloud/ before the workshop. I recommend logging in with an existing Google or GitHub account, if you have one (rather than creating a new account with another password you have to remember).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A postcard</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/collection/day01/02-postcards/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/collection/day01/02-postcards/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the postcards package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;postcards&amp;quot;) Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  packageVersion(&amp;quot;postcards&amp;quot;) [1] ‘0.2.0’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using blogdown</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/collection/day02/02-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/collection/day02/02-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the blogdown package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;blogdoown&amp;quot;) Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  packageVersion(&amp;quot;blogdown&amp;quot;) [1] ‘1.0’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A distill site</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/collection/day01/03-distill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/collection/day01/03-distill/</guid>
      <description>Pre-requisites     First, make sure you have the latest version of the distill package installed from CRAN:
install.packages(&amp;quot;distill&amp;quot;)  Restart your R session. If you use RStudio, use the menu item Session &amp;gt; Restart R or the associated keyboard shortcut:
 Ctrl + Shift + F10 (Windows and Linux) or Command + Shift + F10 (Mac OS).  &amp;lt;!-- --&amp;gt; packageVersion(&amp;quot;distill&amp;quot;) [1] ‘1.2’  Create GitHub repo     Online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warm woolen mittens</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/collection/day02/03-blogdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/collection/day02/03-blogdown/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&#39;m the here-bot cat! Use me to find your way in your website.
Here I am: content/collection/day02/03-blogdown/index.md  To remove me, delete this line inside that file: {{&amp;lt; here &amp;gt;}}
My content section is: collection  My layout is: single-series   part 2!     does this work?      now for some very cool things     more     get ready!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Now Hiring: 2 Funded PhD Students</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/recruit/phd2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/recruit/phd2023/</guid>
      <description>Job Summary     Two fully funded PhD research assistantships are available to join the SpaSES lab at Boise State University to work on a variety of potential projects including:
  Implications of governance preferences for species conservation: Potential projects will draw on a survey of over 25,000 North American residents regarding their perceptions of and preferences for wildlife governance to examine how beliefs regarding the role of government in wildlife management affect conservation strategies for specific species and geographies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing connectivity models</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/blog/intro-graphs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/blog/intro-graphs/</guid>
      <description>pre  code.sourceCode { white-space: pre; position: relative; } pre  code.sourceCode  span { display: inline-block; line-height: 1.25; } pre  code.sourceCode  span:empty { height: 1.2em; } .sourceCode { overflow: visible; } code.sourceCode  span { color: inherit; text-decoration: inherit; } div.sourceCode { margin: 1em 0; } pre.sourceCode { margin: 0; } @media screen { div.sourceCode { overflow: auto; } } @media print { pre  code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conservation Archetypes of Western North America</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/project/archetypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/project/archetypes/</guid>
      <description>Scaling the knowledge obtained from localized case studies to extents and resolutions that match those typically encountered in conservation planning efforts requires identifying recurring patterns in the interactions between people; their local, regional, and national institutions; and the environment. Archetype analysis provides a methodological approach to link the conceptual depth of case studies with the extensive (but often shallow) information in public opinion surveys to characterize these recurrent patterns. Spatial representation of these archetypes can help decision-makers tailor policy and management interventions to the local context while still planning for broader landscape objectives .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Institutional Resistance and Connectivity Conservation For Wildlife</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/project/resistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/project/resistance/</guid>
      <description>coming soon</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Models of Conservation Occurrence</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/project/occurrence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/project/occurrence/</guid>
      <description>Conservation is both an outcome (preventing species extinction or the loss of ecosystem function) and action that society takes to achieve those outcomes. Years of conservation planning research has been devoted to trying to ensure that we take action in the places the &amp;lsquo;need it most&amp;rsquo;. Despite the fact that individuals, organizations, and nation-states continue to devote resources to conservation (the action), many species and ecosystems remain at-risk (the outcome). We combine datasets describing people, politics, economics, institutions, and the environment with Bayesian spatial models to try and understand the enabling conditions that promote conservation as an action and how their alignment (or not) with ecological priorities affects outcomes for nature and people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Spatial Data in R</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/classes/isdr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/classes/isdr/</guid>
      <description>Course Description     Spatial data are ubiquitous and form the basis for many of our inquiries into social, ecological, and evolutionary processes. As such, developing the skills necessary for incorporating spatial data into reproducible statistical workflows is critical. In this course, we will introduce the core components of manipulating spatial data within the R statistical environment including managing vector and raster data, projections, extraction of data values, interpolation, and plotting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A campfire</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/talk/campfire/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/talk/campfire/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m really excited to give this talk! Stay tuned for video and slides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A seedling</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/talk/second-seedling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/talk/second-seedling/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A seedling</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/talk/seedling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 14:15:59 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/talk/seedling/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Feb 2019 13:38:41 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/contact/</guid>
      <description>** Contact page don&amp;rsquo;t contain a body, just the front matter above. See form.html in the layouts folder.
Formspree requires a (free) account and new form to be set up. The link is made on the final published url in the field: Restrict to Domain. It is possible to register up to 2 emails free and you can select which one you want the forms to go to within Formspree in the Settings tab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Typography Styles &amp; Element Examples</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 12:27:33 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/elements/</guid>
      <description>Font Sizes   A A A A A A A A   6rem
(96px) 5rem
(80px) 3rem
(48px) 2.25rem
(36px) 1.5rem
(24px) 1.25rem
(20px) 1rem
(16px) .875rem
(14px)     Type Samples Head&amp;shy;line Sub&amp;shy;head&amp;shy;line Level 1 Heading One page to rule them all...well, not really. This page displays sample typography and page elements to illustrate their style. Things like headings and paragraphs showing the beautiful type scale, form elements, tabular data, and image layouts just to name a few.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contributors</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/contributors/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/contributors/</guid>
      <description>Thank you to all the folks who have contributed both technical and creative skills to this project:
   Desirée De Leon 🦒 (designed 5 of the custom color themes, made illustrations for the workshop, and provided general aesthetic feedback along the way)
   Garrick Aden-Buie 🧙‍♀️ (debugged headroom.js and lent his panelset.js code to the theme)
   Allison Horst 🐕 (awesome illustrations of campfires, seedlings, and evergreens, as well as my R Markdown hedgehog mascot 🦔)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>License</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/license/</guid>
      <description>My blog posts are released under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rewilding and Transformative Governance</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/project/rewilding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/project/rewilding/</guid>
      <description>Indigenous peoples have been managing ecosystems and species since time immemorial. The practices associated with that management have shaped landscapes and the cultures of the people that inhabit them. Contemporary efforts to restore culturally important species and land management practices are increasingly seen as restorative both for ecosystems and people. Yet, such efforts often must navigate a complex suite of governance arrangements owing to the legacy of settler-colonial land tenure and legal systems.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
