<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SPASES Lab Projects on SpaSES Lab</title>
    <link>https://spaseslab.com/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SPASES Lab Projects on SpaSES Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://spaseslab.com/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Conservation Archetypes of Western North America</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/project/archetypes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/project/archetypes/</guid>
      <description>Scaling the knowledge obtained from localized case studies to extents and resolutions that match those typically encountered in conservation planning efforts requires identifying recurring patterns in the interactions between people; their local, regional, and national institutions; and the environment. Archetype analysis provides a methodological approach to link the conceptual depth of case studies with the extensive (but often shallow) information in public opinion surveys to characterize these recurrent patterns. Spatial representation of these archetypes can help decision-makers tailor policy and management interventions to the local context while still planning for broader landscape objectives .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Institutional Resistance and Connectivity Conservation For Wildlife</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/project/resistance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/project/resistance/</guid>
      <description>Conserving species&#39; ability to traverse the landscape is vital for maintaining biodiversity in the face of global change. Connectivity conservation requires identifying important pathways for species&#39; movements and aligning societal support for conservation of those pathways. Contemporary connectivity analyses emphasize the impacts of topography, vegetation and human footprint on species&#39; movements; but largely ignore the role that attitudes, economics and institutions play in practitioners&#39; ability to conserve those movements. Implementation resistance is analogous to biophysical resistance that combines social, economic and institutional factors that promote or impede connectivity conservation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Models of Conservation Occurrence</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/project/occurrence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/project/occurrence/</guid>
      <description>Conservation is both an outcome (preventing species extinction or the loss of ecosystem function) and action that society takes to achieve those outcomes. Years of conservation planning research has been devoted to trying to ensure that we take action in the places the &amp;lsquo;need it most&amp;rsquo;. Despite the fact that individuals, organizations, and nation-states continue to devote resources to conservation (the action), many species and ecosystems remain at-risk (the outcome). We combine datasets describing people, politics, economics, institutions, and the environment with Bayesian spatial models to try and understand the enabling conditions that promote conservation as an action and how their alignment (or not) with ecological priorities affects outcomes for nature and people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rewilding and Transformative Governance</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/project/rewilding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/project/rewilding/</guid>
      <description>Indigenous peoples have been managing ecosystems and species since time immemorial. The practices associated with that management have shaped landscapes and the cultures of the people that inhabit them. Contemporary efforts to restore culturally important species and land management practices are increasingly seen as restorative both for ecosystems and people. Yet, such efforts often must navigate a complex suite of governance arrangements owing to the legacy of settler-colonial land tenure and legal systems.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
