<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>projects on SpaSES Lab</title>
    <link>https://spaseslab.com/tags/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in projects on SpaSES Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://spaseslab.com/tags/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spatial Models of Conservation Occurrence</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/project/occurrence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/project/occurrence/</guid>
      <description>Conservation is both an outcome (preventing species extinction or the loss of ecosystem function) and action that society takes to achieve those outcomes. Years of conservation planning research has been devoted to trying to ensure that we take action in the places the &amp;lsquo;need it most&amp;rsquo;. Despite the fact that individuals, organizations, and nation-states continue to devote resources to conservation (the action), many species and ecosystems remain at-risk (the outcome). We combine datasets describing people, politics, economics, institutions, and the environment with Bayesian spatial models to try and understand the enabling conditions that promote conservation as an action and how their alignment (or not) with ecological priorities affects outcomes for nature and people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rewilding and Transformative Governance</title>
      <link>https://spaseslab.com/project/rewilding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://spaseslab.com/project/rewilding/</guid>
      <description>Indigenous peoples have been managing ecosystems and species since time immemorial. The practices associated with that management have shaped landscapes and the cultures of the people that inhabit them. Contemporary efforts to restore culturally important species and land management practices are increasingly seen as restorative both for ecosystems and people. Yet, such efforts often must navigate a complex suite of governance arrangements owing to the legacy of settler-colonial land tenure and legal systems.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
